本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
小乖角公主说
Princess Love-A-Corn says...
给我买四十二件配饰
Buy my 42 accessories.
我认得这笑声
I know that laugh.
快现身吧
Show yourself.
哟  哟  哟
Well, well, well,
哟  哟  哟  哟  哟  哟  哟  哟  哟
well, well, well, well, well, well, well, well.
咱俩又大眼瞪小眼了
Aren't you a sight for sore eye.
斯坦福・福布里克・派恩斯  我的老朋友
Stanford Filbrick Pines, my old pal.
比尔・赛弗
Bill Cipher.
你是无事不登三宝殿吧
What do you want from me?
哎  还装什么洋蒜啊
Oh, quit playing dumb IQ.
你知道我会回来的
You knew I'd be back.
你以为关掉传送门
You think shutting down that portal
就能打乱我的计划吗
can stop what I have planned?
我一直在做交易
I've been making deals,
和老朋友聊天
chatting with old friends,
为那一天准备着
preparing for the big day.
你可没法保证时空裂痕永远安全哟
You can't keep that rift safe forever.
你会失手的  而且一旦失手
You'll slip up, and when you do...
快滚出去
Get out of here!
你在我们的世界没有统治权
You have no dominion in our world.
现在还没有  但是万事皆可变  斯坦福・派恩斯
Maybe not right now, but things change, Stanford Pines
万事皆可变
Things change.
我必须警告他们
I have to warn them.
他要来了
He's coming.
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
时间轴： Enpistu
翻译： 战忽局副局座  moonywen  溪傲季
怪诞小镇  第二季第十五集
Gravity Falls  S02E15  The Last Mabelcorn
■
校订  后期： Enpistu  WaitinZ
很好  斯坦叔公总该有点正经的桌游吧
All right, Grunkle Stan's gotta have some decent board games.
让我看看  《战斗滑道梯子船》
Let's see, Battle Chutes and Ladder Ships,
《死灵大富翁》 《别吵醒斯大林》
Necronomicopoly, Don't Wake Stalin.
看看这个  《不会出岔子》  桌游版
What's this? "What Could Go Wrong, the board game.
上一对打开盒子的玩家
The last players who opened this box
可没能活着离开
never made it out alive."
嗯  我大概知道我们今天该做什么了
Well, I guess I know what we're going to do today
接下来二十一分钟有事做了
This should take up the next 21 minutes.
家庭会议  家庭会议
Family meeting. Family meeting.
听好了  桑提亚戈
All right, Santiago.
24小时内你必须把哈巴狗带过美墨边境
You have 24 hours to get these pugs across the U.S. Border.
家庭会议  家庭会议
Family meeting, family meeting!
别管这摊子事  快走  快走
No te preocupas. Vamos, vamos.
啊  孩子们  快进来  快进来
Ah, children. Come in, come in.
哟  神秘的卷轴和魔药
Ooh, mysterious scrolls and potions.
是不是我们总算年龄达到
Are you going to tell us we're finally of age
魔法学院招生标准了
to go to wizard school?
提包里是不是有猫头鹰啊
Is there an owl in this bag?
没有  我可以向你保证  就算里面有一只猫头鹰
No. I can assure you, if there's an owl in this bag,
也早就翘辫子了
he's long dead.
现在告诉我  孩子们
Now tell me, children,
你们认不认识这个符号
Do either of you recognize this symbol?
-比尔  -你知道他
- Bill. - You know him?
知道他  他一整个夏天都在折磨我们
Know him? He's been terrorizing us all summer.
我有无数的问题和理论
I have so many questions and theories.
自从被比尔变成袜子活布偶后
Dipper's been pretty paranoid
迪普就一直疑神疑鬼的
since Bill turned him into a living sock puppet.
重要的是  我们把他击垮了两次
The important thing is, we defeated him twice.
一次是用猫猫拳  一次是用挠痒痒
Once with kittens, and once with tickles.
真正的战斗比说起来要英勇得多
It was a lot more heroic than it sounds.
你们和比尔的种种过节
The fact that you've dealt with Bill
非常非常严重
is gravely serious.
你是怎么认识比尔的
So how do you know Bill?
迪普  我这辈子见过无数邪恶的生物
I have encountered many dark beings in my time, Dipper.
重要的是  他的力量正愈发强大
What matters is, his powers are growing stronger,
一旦他实施计划
and if he pulls off his plans,
我们这个家谁都逃不出魔爪
No one in this family will be safe.
幸好有个方法能保护我们
Fortunately, there should be a way to shield us
不被他的精神控制影响  将小屋变为比尔的禁区
from his mental tricks. A way to Bill-proof the shack.
只要把月长石放到这里  这里和这里
All I have to do is place moonstones here, here and here,
洒点水银  我再想想
sprinkle some mercury, and let's see,
我总是忘掉这最后一样原料
I always forget the last ingredient.
独角兽鬃毛
Unicorn hair.
这样原料  不会很难找吧
That's not, like, rare, is it?
没希望了
It's hopeless.
独角兽居住在魔法森林深处
Unicorns reside deep within an enchanted glade,
而只有内心善良  纯洁无暇
and their hairs can only be obtained
身负魔法重任前往的人
by a pure, good-hearted person who goes on
才能获取它的鬃毛
a magical quest to find them.
阿福叔公  求求你让我去吧
Grunkle Ford, can I please go on this quest?
我对独角兽可是超级超级痴迷啊
I am literally obsessed with unicorns.
我生下来会说的第一个词就是独角兽
My first word was unicorn,
我有一次还把路锥贴在马头上
I once made my own unicorn by taping a traffic cone
创造了自己的独角兽
to a horse's head.
禁止入内
宠物公园
你再看看我现在穿的是什么毛衣
Are you even looking at the sweater I'm wearing right now?
更不用说  现在这屋子里只有我的心灵是
Not to mention that I'm probably the most pure-of-heart person
最纯洁无瑕的
in this room.
-她说得好有道理  -我竟无法反驳
- That's true. She has a point. - Can't argue there.
那总能让我去找独角兽鬃毛了吧
So can I go on a mission to get that hair?
求您了  求您了  让我洒热血都行
Please, please, please. I'll give you my blood!
很好  取毛路布满了艰难险阻
Very well, but it won't be easy.
-带上这个  和这个  -哇
- Take this, and this. - Ooh.
太长时间没在这个时空待过了
I haven't been in this dimension for a while.
给小孩子武器不会有什么事吧
It's okay to give children weapons, right?
肯定不会啦  哥们儿
Come on, dawg.
快跑  是条子
It's the cops. Gun it!
糖糖  格兰达  温蒂  把下午的时间腾出来
Candy, Grenda, Wendy, clear the afternoon.
她能拿回鬃毛的可能性有多大
So what are the odds she gets that hair?
几乎不可能  我跟独角兽打过交道
Unlikely. I've dealt with unicorns before,
如果让我用一个字描述他们
and if I had to describe them in one word,
这个字就是“损”
it would be "Frustrating."
-那我们该怎么防范比尔呢  -跟我来
- So what are we gonna do about Bill? - Follow me.
欢迎来到我的私人研究室
Welcome to my private study.
这个地方藏有我最古老和最隐秘的知识
The place where I keep my most ancient and secret knowledge.
就连你叔公斯坦都不知道这个地方
Even your Uncle Stan doesn't know about this place.
迪普  快跟上
Dipper, come along.
如果小屋没法成为比尔的禁区
If we can't Bill-proof the shack,
我们就只能退求其次了
we're gonna have to do the next best thing.
让我们的思维无法被比尔读取
We're gonna have to Bill-proof our minds.
总算能出任务真是高兴
It's nice to finally be out on a mission.
只有我们这些姑娘
Just us gals.
我可不是来和闺蜜聊天的
Forget the gal talk.
我来这儿是看  摸  甚至变成一只独角兽的
I'm here to meet, touch, and/or become a unicorn.
我听说要是你舔独角兽的脖子
I hear, if you lick a unicorn's neck,
尝起来会是你最喜欢的味道
it tastes like your favorite flavor in the world.
糖糖  我保证你会舔到独角兽脖子的
Candy, I will make sure you lick that unicorn's neck,
因为我关心我的朋友
because I care about my friends.
说实话  我大概五岁的时候
Honestly, I stopped believing in unicorns
就不相信有独角兽了
when I was, like, five years old.
我跟你们这帮小孩子来
I'm just coming along to keep you kids
是为了保证你们不掉进捉熊陷阱
from walking into a bear trap.
停下  这里就是魔法森林的中心了
Stop! This is the magic part of the forest.
让我看看  矮人营地在那边
Let's see, the gnome tavern is over there.
仙女美甲店在那边
The fairy nail salon is over there.
这里说如果要召唤独角兽
It says to summon the unicorn,
必须要用老年人沉重的嗓音
one must bellow this ancient chant,
吟唱古老的韵字
droned only by the deepest-voiced druids of old.
交给我吧
On it.
赌十块钱  什么事都不会发生
I bet you ten bucks nothing happens.
接受挑战
I'll take that bet.
面包车上喷的图案果然是真的
The paintings airbrushed on the sides of vans were true.
我的亲娘啊
Mother of mothers!
-我的梦想成真了  -不会吧
- Dream of dreams! - No way!
欢迎光临我这迷人的房间
Hark. Visitors to my room of enchantment.
我的天啊  我的天啊  你叫什么名字
Oh, my gosh, oh, my gosh. What's your name?
我叫瑟拉斯贝拉贝莎贝  唯一幸存的独角兽
I am Celestabellabethabelle, last of my kind.
快来  快来  把鞋子脱掉就好
Come in, come in. Just take off your shoes.
我特别看不惯鞋子
I have a whole thing about shoes.
慢着  所有人都要脱鞋哦
Uh-uh, I'm talking to all of you.
瑟拉斯贝拉贝莎贝  我们从遥远的地方慕名而来
Celestabellabethabelle, we have journeyed far and wide.
走了大概一个小时
About an hour.
身负保卫家庭的重任
On a mission to protect our family
需要你的魔法鬃毛
with your magical hair.
糖糖  快抓住机会
This is your chance, Candy.
舔脖子  快舔啊
Lick the neck. Lick it.
很好  请来接受我迷人的鬃毛吧
Very well. To receive a lock of my enchanted hair,
向前走  内心纯洁无暇的女孩
step forth, girl of pure, perfect heart.
在下
Presenting...
梅宝
Mabel!
什么  就你
What?! You?
孩子  独角兽可以看穿你的心灵
A unicorn can see deep inside your heart, child.
而你可干了坏事  我说的是  坏事
And you have done wrong. Wrong, I say.
我好像确实经常嘲笑迪普啊
I guess I do make fun of Dipper a lot.
还用弩箭把窗子打破了
And I did just shatter a window with a crossbow.
你做的坏事让我垂泪
Your bad deeds make me cry.
当你的心灵纯洁无暇的时候再回来
Come back when you're pure of heart.
出口在那边
The exit is that way.
鞋子  鞋子  把鞋穿走
Shoes, shoes, take your shoes.
这里可不是什么  什么  鞋店
This isn't some... some... shoe store.
梅宝  别为她的话烦心了
Hey, Mabel, don't let her get to you.
是啊  我才不会相信一匹化了妆的马
Yeah, I wouldn't trust a horse that wears makeup.
不  姐妹们  她说的对
No, girls, she's right.
我曾经是一个非常善良的人
I used to be one of the sweetest people I knew,
但最近  我却在行善的生涯中
but recently, I've been slacking
懈怠偷懒了
in the whole goodness department.
今天起  我们要改过自新
Well, today, we're gonna fix it.
从现在开始
From this moment forth,
我要做很多很多好事
I'm gonna do so many good deeds,
我要成为重力泉最纯洁的心
I'll have the purest heart in Gravity Falls.
那  那只鸟没事
That... that bird is fine.
那比尔到底是谁
So what is Bill exactly?
谁都不确定
No one knows for sure.
他的真实动机和来源众说纷纭
Accounts differ of his true motivations and origins.
我知道他的年龄比银河系还要大
I know he's older than our galaxy,
也更加古怪
and far more twisted.
他没有肉体形态  只能透过思维空间
Not a physical form, he can only project himself
我们的世界
思维空间
噩梦地带
入侵我们的思想
into our thoughts through the mindscape.
所以他才想要这个
That's why he wants this.
虽然我已经拆掉了传送门  但有了这点破绽
I dismantled the portal, but with this tear,
比尔还是可以进入到现实世界
Bill still has a way into our reality.
为了触及这道时空裂痕
To get his hands on this rift,
他不惜迷惑或操纵任何人
he would trick or possess anyone.
那怎样才能阻止比尔进入我们的思想呢
So how do we keep Bill out of our minds?
有很多种方法
There's a number of ways.
我的方法是在脑袋里装了一块金属板
I personally had a metal plate installed in my head.
真会说笑
Good one.
但这台机器则更为保险
But this machine is safer.
它会扫描你的大脑
It will scan your mind,
将你思维里的生物电波加密
bio-electrically encrypting your thoughts
使比尔无法阅读
so Bill can't read them.
现在对着你的思维打个招呼吧
Now say hello to your thoughts.
天呐  真不敢相信我和这本日志的作者见面了
Oh, man, I can't believe I'm with the author.
我的裤裆拉链掉了吗
Is my fly down?
迪斯科姑娘  一起跳
Disco girl, coming through
温蒂  温蒂  温蒂  温蒂
Wendy, Wendy, Wendy, Wendy.
你还是忽略最后一条吧
You might wanna ignore that last one.
对了  你从没告诉过我你和比尔的过往
By the way, you never told me what your history with Bill was.
迪普  你信任我吗
Dipper, do you trust me?
唔  信任啊  但是
Well, yeah, but...
那你就应该相信  那些过往并不重要
Then you'll trust that that's not important.
现在集中精神  是时候强化你的思想了
Now focus. It's time to strengthen your mind.
好啦  梅宝  是时候强大你的内心了
All right, Mabel, it's time to strengthen your heart.
分享微笑
Share a smile
做个美梦
Dream a dream
日行一善
Doin' some good deed
献 血
太好了  一千件好事
Boom! 1,000 good deeds.
这回让那匹独角兽扫描我的心
When that unicorn scans my heart,
她一定会说我是毫无疑问  百分之百  真真正正的
she's gonna say I'm absolutely, 100%, bona fide...
一点也不纯洁
Not pure of heart.
太好了  等等  啥
Boo-ya! Wait, what?
这怎么可能
How is that even possible?
梅宝绝对是个大好人  你这偏心的臭马
Mabel's a straight-up saint, you judgmental hoof bag.
求你告诉我我到底哪里做错了
Please tell me what I'm doing wrong.
试图做好事使自己看起来更优秀
Doing good deeds to make yourself look better
出发点就错了
isn't good at all.
更何况你现在压死了大概有十只蒲公英吧
Not to mention you're crushing, like, ten dandelions right now.
这些都是孩子们的梦想
Those are basically children's dreams.
对不起  梅宝  你是坏人并不是我的错
I'm sorry, Mabel. It's not my fault you're a bad person.
梅宝  等等  快回来
Mabel, wait. Come back.
不介意的话我先失陪了
Now if you'll excuse me,
三点钟的时候我要在彩虹前摆造型
I have a 3:00 posing in front of a rainbow.
算了  梅宝  别被这种事打击到了
Come on, Mabel. Don't beat yourself up over this.
我们还是忘记那可笑的独角兽鬃毛吧
Let's forget about getting that dumb unicorn hair.
姐妹们  这已经不再是鬃毛的问题了
It's not about the hair anymore, guys.
而是我这个人
It's about me.
亲切和善良才是我存在的意义
Being kind and sweet is what makes me who I am.
如果我不再是好人  那我是谁呢
If I'm not a good person, who am I?
我要想出一件好事  能让我变得
I'm not leaving this spot until I think of a deed
像瑟拉斯贝拉贝莎贝一样好  否则绝不离开
that makes me as good as Celestabellabethabelle.
但是梅宝
But Mabel...
让我一个人静静
Just leave me be.
妹妹们  要我说  这件事对她来说是个沉重的负担
Guys, if you ask me, this whole thing is a serious load.
梅宝算是我见过最好的人了
Mabel's, like, the best person I've ever met.
我们已经尝试过以善意的方式去取得毛发
We tried getting that hair the good way.
现在该采用温蒂的方式了
Now it's time we try the Wendy way.
你是在建议我们使用暴力  搞破坏吗
Are you suggesting violence? Sabotage?
这么做梅宝不会喜欢的
Mabel's not going to like that.
梅宝根本不需要知道
Mabel doesn't need to know.
听着  是时候该摒弃完美主义的想法
Look, it's time we stopped trying to be so "Perfect,"
做回我们自己了
and be who we really are.
我们是狂野  愤怒  凶猛的动物
We're crazed, angry, sweaty animals.
我们不是独角兽
We're not unicorns.
我们是女人
We're women!
我们想要什么就必须搞到手
And we take what we want.
-说得好  -没错
- Yeah! - Yes!
是不是太过了
Too much?
待会儿我们这么做
Here's what we're gonna do.
恶矮人酒吧  松鼠停后面
给我来一大壶最香甜的金银花酒
Get me a flagon of your daintiest honeysuckle, please.
我需要检查一下你的身份证件
I'm gonna need to see some I.D.
是条子  快卧倒
The cops. Hit the deck.
我在找一个知道怎么撂倒独角兽的家伙
I'm lookin' for someone who knows how to take down a unicorn.
别想耍花招
No tricks or games.
我们是人类   我们要什么就必须搞到手
We are human. We take what we want.
没错
Yeah!
仙尘
Fairy dust.
一整袋仙尘足够让一只独角兽睡得死死的
A whole magic bag's enough to put a unicorn out cold,
不过要我帮忙
but if I do you a favor,
你们得为我做点事
you gotta do something for me.
说吧  矮子
Just spill it, half-pint.
在森林本区  蝴蝶交易是非法的
Butterfly trafficking is illegal in this part of the forest.
但是我很喜欢蝴蝶
But I like butterflies.
他们在我脸上挠痒痒  弄得我大笑
They tickle my face and make me laugh.
给我一袋蝴蝶  我们就做交易
Bring me a bag of butterflies, and we got a deal.
两袋仙尘  我们说好了的
Two bags of fairy dust, just like we agreed.
你从哪里搞来的这玩意儿
Where do you get this stuff?
人人爱吃香肠  却没人关心香肠的做法
Everyone likes sausage, but no one likes to know how it's made.
你真恶心
You disgust me.
你们拿魔药  我拿蝴蝶
You've got your poison, I've got mine.
我们公平交易
We made a deal.
是的  交易结束了
Yeah, well, the deal is off.
不准动  你被捕了  趴下  趴下
Freeze. You're under arrest. Get down, get down.
这些蝴蝶不是我的
These butterflies aren't mine.
我发誓  我是被陷害的
I swear. I've been framed.
跟被我们打扮成法官的可爱猫头鹰说去吧
Tell it to the adorable owl we've dressed as a judge.
我的那份呢
My cut.
帮斯坦削铅笔  灌满蜂蜜罐  给苏斯织围巾  给猫刷毛
好事  好事
Good deeds, good deeds.
根本不够好啊
Oh, that's not good enough.
加油  梅宝  你可以做得更好
Come on, Mabel, you can do better than that.
嘶叫，祈祷，小跑
是啊  我当然也想去旅游
Oh, sure, sure. I wish I could travel,
可是当前的经济状况又不允许
but it's just not feasible in this economy.
搞啥
What the hay?
睡觉吧  快睡
Sleep now. Sleep.
不  等等  停下
No, wait! Stop!
梅宝
Mabel, sh!
你会吵醒她的
You'll wake her up.
但姐妹们  这是在做坏事
But this is wrong, guys.
可保护神秘小屋是件好事
But protecting the shack is good.
什么
What?
是我的眼睛看错了吗
Doth my eyes deceive me?
你永远也也得不到纯洁之心
You shall never be pure of heart.
不  你不明白
No, you don't understand.
我只想变得和你一样好
I just wanna be good like you.
有没有搞错  你不是在逗我吧
Whoa, whoa, whoa, you gotta be kiddin' me.
傻贝  你又在玩这套
Yo, C-Beth, are you seriously pullin'
“纯洁之心”的骗局了吗
this "Pure of heart" Scam again?
你可搞得一团糟了
That is messed up, man.
等等  骗局
Wait. Scam?
孩子们  独角兽并不能看到你们的内心
Kid, unicorns can't see into your heart.
我们这只没用的角只会发光
All our dumb horns can do is glow,
指向最近的彩虹
point toward the nearest rainbow,
以及播放一些锐舞音乐
and play rave music.
没错  整件“纯洁之心”闹剧
Yeah, the whole "Pure of heart" Racket
只是我们编造的谎话  好让人类别来烦我们
is just a line we use to get humans to leave us alone.
伙计们  别说了嘛
Guys, shut up.
自始至终
All this time.
自始至终  我都以为我是一个坏人
All this time, I thought I was a bad person.
梅宝之罪
但你比我可恶多了
But you're even worse than I am!
好吧  你已经知道我们的秘密了
Okay, fine, so you learned our secret.
我们是混蛋  好了吧
We're jerks, okay.
我们的鬃毛多多  对自身也没什么大用处
We have more hair than we know what to do with,
但我们偏要自己留着
and we keep it to ourselves
就为了让你们人类闹心
just to tick humans off.
你能拿我们怎么办  啊
What are you gonna do about it, huh? Huh?
你能怎么办
What are you gonna do?
喔  加油  梅宝
Whoo! Go, Mabel.
加入黑暗势力吧
Join the dark side.
战斗  战斗  战斗
Fight, fight, fight!
这么说你想动武
So it's a fight you want.
那我们就用武力遂了你们的愿
Well, then it's a fight you're gonna get.
正在扫描思想
这真是没完没了
Uh, this is taking forever.
我这么坐着多久啦
How long have I been doing this for?
为什么他要对比尔的事表现得如此神秘兮兮
Why does he have to be so mysterious about Bill?
我能接受事实的
I can handle the truth.
我想知道阿福叔公在想些什么
I wonder what Great-uncle Ford is thinking.
使用这台机器  就能向你展示他的想法
Use the machine. It'll show you his thoughts.
我不该那么做
I shouldn't.
他不会知道
He won't know.
而且最终他也会告诉你的
He's going to tell you eventually.
你对比尔了解得越深
The more you know about Bill,
你就能帮得越多
the more you can help.
老天  我真的很擅长找合理的借口
Man, I am really good at rationalizing.
是的  的确  没错
Yes, you are.
只是偷偷看一眼
Just a little peek.
关于比尔  你隐瞒了些什么
What are you hiding about Bill?
这些想法是从哪里冒出来的
Where are these ideas comin' from?
你和谁在合作
Who are you working with?
我兄弟是个危险的万事通
My brother's a dangerous know-it-all.
他不惜迷惑或操纵任何人
He would trick or possess anyone.
就这么定了  从现在开始  直到时间尽头
Then it's a deal. From now until the end of time.
把我植入到你的脑海中吧  斯坦福
Just plug me into your mind, Stanford.
请叫我朋友
Please, call me a friend.
阿福叔公和比尔
Ford and Bill?
你不该读我的心
You shouldn't have done that.
你为什么要和比尔握手
Why were you shaking hands with Bill?
你说过  比尔为了得到这东西可能操纵任何人
You said Bill could possess anyone so he could get this.
当心
Careful!
把时空裂痕给我  现在就拿来  孩子
Hand me the rift. Now, boy.
为什么你要扫描我的思想
Why were you really scanning my thoughts?
你现在是比尔吗
Are you Bill right now?
你先冷静下来
Now just calm down.
松树  你是想要那样叫我吗
Pine Tree. Is that what you were going to call me?
我是想说拜托了  孩子
I was gonna say please, kid.
阿福叔公让我保护时空裂痕
Great-uncle Ford told me to protect the rift.
你再靠近一步  我就开枪了
Get one step closer and I'll shoot.
我要把你从阿福叔公的脑袋里除掉
I'll erase you right out of Ford's head.
是我  迪普  我就是你叔公
It's me, Dipper. It's your uncle.
不能相信任何人  不能相信任何人
Trust no one, trust no one.
-不能相信  -把它给我
- Trust... - Hand it to me.
你放开我
Let go of me.
冷静一下
Now just calm down.
冷静  看着我的眼睛
Calm down. Look into my eyes.
看我的瞳孔
Look at my pupils.
是我  迪普  真的是我
It's me, Dipper. It's me.
我刚才差点消除你的意识
I tried to erase your mind.
真的对不起
I'm so sorry.
没事  迪普
It's okay, Dipper.
另外  我的意识是消除不了的  记得吗
Besides, my mind can't be erased anyway, remember?
不过  如果刚才真的是比尔的话
If that really was Bill, though,
那么你干得很漂亮
you would've done great.
我年轻的时候  也应该多像你这样
I should've been more like you when I was young.
迪普  我真是傻  还准备遮掩这些事
Dipper, I was a fool to try to hide all this.
我急着让你做好准备对付比尔的诡计
The reason I've been trying to prepare you
因为我曾经上过比尔的当
for Bill's tricks is because Bill tricked me.
那是我人生中最愧疚的事
It's the biggest regret of my life.
比尔一开始并不是我的敌人  迪普
Bill wasn't always my enemy, Dipper.
我曾经以为他是我的朋友
I used to think he was my friend,
很久很久以前
long, long ago.
我对重力泉的研究遇到了瓶颈
I had hit a roadblock in my investigation of Gravity Falls,
直到我在一个洞穴里找到了一些神秘的文字
until I found some mysterious writing in a cave.
是关于一个无所不知的生物的古老咒语
Ancient incantations about a being with answers.
它警告我不要读那些文字
It warned me not to read them,
但是我当时已经孤注一掷
but I was desperate.
我大声读出了那些铭文  不过什么也没有发生
I read the inscription aloud, but nothing happened,
直到那天午后
until later that afternoon,
我做了一个古怪至极的梦
when I had the most peculiar dream.
你好呀  聪明的家伙
Hiya, smart guy.
别被我吓得心脏病发
Whoa, don't have a heart attack.
你还没到九十二岁呢
You're not 92 yet.
你是谁
Who are you?
我叫比尔  你叫斯坦福・派恩斯
Name's Bill, and your name's Stanford Pines,
那个改变了世界的男人
the man who changed the world.
但是我言之过早了
But I'm getting ahead of ourselves.
放松  想不想下一轮跨次元象棋
Let's relax. Care for a game of interdimensional chess?
或者喝杯茶
Have a cup of tea.
他告诉我他是个灵感之神
He told me he was a muse,
他每个世纪都会选择一个才华横溢的人触发灵感
that he chose one brilliant mind a century to inspire.
我真是个傻瓜
What a fool I was.
被他的花言巧语和诡计蒙蔽了双眼
Blinded by his flattery and games.
他成为了我的研究助手
He became my research assistant.
他可以随他所愿  自由地进出我的脑海
He was free to move in and out of my mind as he pleased;
我们是伙伴
we were partners.
当他告诉我  我可以建一个通向其他世界的门
When he told me that I could complete my research
来完成我的研究
by building a gateway to other worlds,
我相信了他
I trusted him.
他说这就是造就天才的方式
He said this was the way genius happened--
加上朋友的一点儿小帮助
with a little help from a friend.
看上去我似乎离人生最大的成就
It seemed that I was on the verge
只有一步之遥
of my greatest achievement.
直到我的研究伙伴瞥见了
Until my partner got a glimpse
比尔真正的计划
of Bill's true plans.
比尔  你骗了我
Bill, you lied to me!
这个传送门到底通向哪里
Where does that portal really lead?
看来超级天才先生终于变得聪明了
Looks like Mr. Brainiac finally got smart.
这么说吧  当传送门完成充能的时候
Let's just say that when that portal finishes charging up,
你的时空就知道什么叫热闹啦  对吗  伙计们
your dimension is gonna learn how to party, right, guys?
不  我会阻止你的  我会关上这扇门
No. I'll stop you. I'll shut it down!
遵守约定吧  六指
A deal's a deal, sixer.
你无法阻止我们两个世界之间纽带的形成
You can't stop the bridge between our world from coming.
但是看着你努力尝试  很有趣
But it would be fun to watch you try.
甚至是傻的可爱
Cute even.
我被背叛了
I'd been betrayed.
我关掉了传送门
I shut the portal down,
切断了比尔的世界和我们世界之间的连接
severing the link between Bill's world and ours.
我不得不把我的操作指南藏起来
I had to hide my instructions
这样就再也没有人能完成比尔的研究
so no one could ever finish Bill's work.
自那以后  比尔就在等待传送门重新开启
Bill's been waiting for the gateway to reopen ever since.
它要做的仅仅是触碰这个裂痕
All he needs to do is get his hands on this rift.
对比尔而言  这是一场游戏
To Bill, it's just a game.
但是对我们来说  可能意味着我们世界的毁灭
But to us, it would mean the end of our world.
我的天
Oh, man.
的确是天大的事
"Oh, man" Indeed.
我对之前的事感到很尴尬
I'm so embarrassed about earlier.
我真是个白痴
I'm such an idiot.
从现在开始  我们之间再也不会有秘密了
From now on, no more secrets between us.
孩子  咱俩不是头两个被比尔耍的白痴
We're not the first two idiots to be tricked by Bill, boy,
但是如果我们一同合作  我们会是最后的两个
but if we work together, we could be the last.
但是比尔怎么办  我弄坏了那个机器
But what about Bill? I broke the machine.
现在我们没办法保护小屋了
Now we have no way to protect the shack.
刚才是有人说到独角兽鬃毛吗
Did someone say unicorn hair?
事实上  没有
Uh, no, actually.
要是说了就完美了
Oh. That would've been perfect.
无所谓  反正我们拿到独角兽的鬃毛啦
Either way, we got some unicorn hair.
还有独角兽的眼泪  独角兽的睫毛
Also some unicorn tears, unicorn eyelashes.
最后还给了我们这个珠宝箱
They finally gave us this treasure chest
请我们离开
to get rid of us.
这不可能
It can't be.
今天是了不起的一天  姑娘们
This is a great day, girls.
有了这独角兽鬃毛
With this unicorn hair,
我们就能让小屋完全防住
we'll be able to completely shield the shack
比尔的读心术了
from Bill's mind-reading tricks.
-这样可以吗  -岂止是可以  很完美
- Is it okay? - Better than okay. It's perfect.
你保护了你的家人
You've protected your family.
梅宝  你真是一个好孩子
You're a good person, Mabel.
阿福叔公  谢谢夸奖
Thanks, Grunkle Ford,
但今天我明白了  道德观是相对的
but today I learned that morality is relative.
发财啦
Money!
完美
Perfect.
这东西能帮我们防住比尔
This will protect us from Bill.
只要我们在这里面  我们的意识就是安全的
As long as we're inside, our minds are safe.
我大概操纵不了小屋里的人了
I guess I can't possess anyone inside the shack,
看来不得不到外面去找我的
so I 'll just have to find my next pawn
下一个小卒啦
on the outside.